<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quentier</title>
    <link>https://d1vanov.github.io/quentier/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Quentier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Dmitry Ivanov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 07:48:54 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://d1vanov.github.io/quentier/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quentier local storage implementation overview</title>
      <link>https://d1vanov.github.io/quentier/blog/quentier-local-storage-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 07:48:54 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d1vanov.github.io/quentier/blog/quentier-local-storage-overview/</guid>
      <description>This post continues the exploration of Quentier&amp;rsquo;s internals: here we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the implementation details of Quentier&amp;rsquo;s local storage.
As I mentioned in the brief technical overview post, the local storage within libquentier uses SQLite as its backend i.e. all the data downloaded from Evernote (or user&amp;rsquo;s own data in case of local account) is stored within a SQLite database. However, it is just an implementation detail: the fact of SQLite usage is completely opaque to any clients of local storage functionality within libquentier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation of Quentier&#39;s dependencies</title>
      <link>https://d1vanov.github.io/quentier/blog/quentier-installation-of-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 11:07:39 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d1vanov.github.io/quentier/blog/quentier-installation-of-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>Updated 2019-05-03
Table of contents  Introduction Dependencies Linux Mac Windows  Building dependencies with Visual Studio  Preparing the environment Building boost program options library Building OpenSSL Building libiconv Building zlib Building libxml2 Building libhunspell Building tidy-html5 Building qtkeychain Building Google breakpad  Building dependencies with MinGW  Building boost program options library Building OpenSSL Building libiconv Building zlib Building libxml2 Building libhunspell Building tidy-html5 Building qtkeychain    Introduction Quentier has a fair share of dependencies and their installation is a complex enough procedure, especially on Windows platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quentier internals overview</title>
      <link>https://d1vanov.github.io/quentier/blog/quentier-technical-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 23:20:33 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d1vanov.github.io/quentier/blog/quentier-technical-overview/</guid>
      <description>This post is primarily for developers who would like to contribute to Quentier but aren&amp;rsquo;t quite sure where to start. Here the high-level overview of the app design is explained.
First, let&amp;rsquo;s briefly enumerate the kinds of technology used in Quentier project:
 Qt/C++ CMake SQLite JavaScript CSS (a bit)  If you are familiar with any of these technologies, you are most likely able to help developing Quentier! However, note that there are some specific ways in which these technologies are used in the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brief overview of Quentier features</title>
      <link>https://d1vanov.github.io/quentier/blog/quentier-brief-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 08:16:09 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d1vanov.github.io/quentier/blog/quentier-brief-overview/</guid>
      <description>In this post I describe in more details what Quentier app is capable of by the current moment.
First of all, please note that at the time of this writing Quentier is in public alpha stage. That means the project is very fresh, some things are unpolished while some other things might just refuse to work due to some unforeseen circumstances. It is pretty normal to go through this stage for any new software project, just be aware of that and don’t expect too much from the current version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>https://d1vanov.github.io/quentier/blog/helloworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 08:07:11 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d1vanov.github.io/quentier/blog/helloworld/</guid>
      <description>This blog is dedicated to Quentier — an open source desktop note taking app which can be used as Evernote client or just for local note taking without the necessity to even have the Evernote account. Quentier is free software distributed under the terms of GNU GPL v.3. The core functionality of Quentier is encapsulated in libquentier library which is distributed under the terms of GNU LGPL v.3.
Let me briefly introduce myself as the author of Quentier: my name is Dmitry Ivanov, I&amp;rsquo;m a 29 years old software developer from Saint-Petersburg, Russia.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>